Previously on "marvel's agents of S.H.I.E.L.D."...
"神盾局特工"前情提要...
I know that...Agent coulson was killed in action.
我知道...寇森特工在行动中牺牲
Welcome to level seven.
欢迎来到第七级
Some say it was only for 8 seconds,But I feel different.
他们说我只死了八秒钟 但我感觉不一样了
What is centipede?
人体蜈蚣是什么?
It's an intravenous filter for his blood.
是用于过滤他静脉血液的装置
Very similar to the serum Dr.Erskine developed in the '40s for the...
很像厄斯金博士在40年代 创造的血清 为了制造...
Super soldiers.
超级士兵
Listen,doctor,your product works.
听着 医生 你的产品有效果了
It appears the volatility in the serum has been neutralized.
看起来 血清的不稳定性被中和了
Who is the woman you referred to?
你说的女人是谁?
Some rich girl in a flower dress.
某个穿花裙子的黑富美
We all have to do things that make us uncomfortable If we are ever to get our toy soldiers off the shelf.
我们都必须做一些不情愿的事 才能让我们的玩具士兵成功出品
漫威出品
漫威出品
***
黑文沃斯联邦监狱
That seat is taken.
那个座位有人了
Perimeter breach,quad four!
外围被入侵 四分队!
three guys just crashed the prison!
有三个家伙刚刚穿透了监狱!
Time to go.
该走了
Sir.
长官
Excuse me?
你说什么?
Time to go,sir.
该走了 长官
It's time to go,sir!
该走了 长官!
-=http://bbs.sfile2012.com=- Proudly Presents
-=伊甸园美剧 http://bbs.sfile2012.com=- -=伊甸园字幕站 http://ytet.org=- 荣誉出品 本字幕仅供学习交流，严禁用于商业途径
-=http://bbs.sfile2012.com/bbs=- Sync: YTET- 邦德猪
-=YTET-伊甸园字幕组=- 翻译:安 梨涡浅笑 煮小蛋蛋 怡豆 校对:阿衡提醒观众前有大坑注意 时间轴: 邦德猪
marvels.agents.of.s.h.i.e.l.d s01e10
神盾局特工 第一季 第10集
- Mission briefing in five. - Okay.
- 五分钟后任务简报 - 好
Katherine shane?
凯瑟琳・谢恩?
Do you know her?
你认识她吗?
We ran a few ops together in the '90s.
九十年代时我们一起干过活儿
Smart,resourceful.
聪明 点子多
Had a soft spot for truffaut movies.
对特吕福的电影没有抵抗力
Easy there,charm school.
别这样啊 知道你魅力十足
According to these files,agent shane could be my mom.
根据这些档案 谢恩特工可能是我妈妈
Even if shane was the agent Who dropped you off at the orphanage,It doesn't mean she's your mother.
就算是谢恩把你放到孤儿院去的 她也不一定是你生母
I started looking into all the female agents Active when I was born.
我调查了我出生时 在神盾局出任务的女特工
Needle,haystack,I know.But then I factored in age and marital status,
我知道这是大海捞针 但我用年龄和婚姻状况做参数
And then I built a program to narrow down the field.
确立了一套程式来缩小范围
You're still looking at a long road.
但这机会还是不大啊
Well,it would be a lot shorter If I could access more files.
如果我能多看到一些档案 就能快多了
Maybe you could remove my internet nanny?
没准你能弄掉我的网络小保姆?
- I'm talking about my tracking bracelet. - I got that.
- 我在说我的追踪手镯 - 我知道
- So you'll take it off. - No.
- 那你会拿掉它咯? - 不
But I asked may to look Into S.H.I.E.L.D.'s more restricted files.
但我已经让梅调查局里更机密的文档了
I was kind of hoping to keep this private.
我想着这事儿要保密的
Agent may specializes in private.
梅特工特别擅长保密
Let's go.
走吧
Nice feint.
佯攻不错
I read your file. I know you favor your left.
我看过你的档案 知道你偏爱用左手
That's in there?What else?
这事也在档案里? 还有些什么?
Nothing that's news.
没啥新鲜的
You don't play well with others.
你和别人相处有问题
I think I've proven that I can...
我觉得我已经证明我很好相处了...
...More than once.
...还不止一次
Not here.
别在这里说
Towel down.
擦擦汗
I need you both in the command center in five.
你们俩五分钟后去指挥中心
At 0-800 hours,Three men infiltrated the havenworth federal penitentiary.
早上八点 有三人潜入了黑文沃斯联邦监狱
Infiltrated?More like cannonballed.
潜入? 我看更像是横冲直撞进去的
They were in and out in less then two minutes.
两分钟之内进出完毕
Left no prints at the scene,but we do have one lead.
现场没留下指纹 但我们有一个线索
centipede.
人体蜈蚣
Seems they salvaged some of their research from hong kong.
看来他们从香港抢救了一部分研究成果
So we were right.Chan's platelets solved their combustion problem.
我们说对了 陈的血小板 的确解决了自爆的问题
Now they can create super soldiers With no fear of explosion.
他们现在可以不用害怕爆炸 就能制造超级士兵了
Maybe don't get so excited about it.
也许别因为这个太激动了
Two of centipede's labs have been destroyed,But they keep popping back up.
两个人体蜈蚣实验室被毁了 但他们总会再次冒头
Now they have at least three of these guys,maybe more.
现在他们有至少三个这样的家伙 甚至更多
Who did they break out?
他们救走了谁?
Edison po,former marine,Expert in tactics and rapid response.
艾迪森・坡 前海军陆战队员 擅长战略和快速反应
He fell off the grid in '08,Reappeared 18 months ago at a diner in boston.
他08年起就销声匿迹 18个月前在波士顿一个餐厅出现
Where he stabbed a friend's eyes out.
他在那儿把一个朋友的眼睛剜出来了
With a steak knife,then finished his meal.
用切牛排的刀 然后他还吃完了饭
That's funny.Po doesn't look crazy.
真稀奇 坡看起来没多疯狂啊
I'm kidding.The guy is a walking mug shot.
开玩笑的 这人就长了一张罪犯的脸
Which means he shouldn't be too hard to track down.
这意味着他不应该太难找
Finding po and these centipede soldiers Is a top priority for S.H.I.E.L.D.
找到坡和这些蜈蚣士兵是神盾局的当务之急
We'll be running point,but we won't be working alone.
我们就是打头阵的 但不必孤军奋战
What team did hq send for backup?
上头给我们拨了哪个队做后援?
Not a team -- a person,Someone who can help us fight fire with fire.
不是队伍 是个人 能帮我们以毒攻毒的人
Somebody we worked with before?
我们以前和这人合作过吗?
Not exactly.
不能算合作
Did I beat captain america's time?
我打破美国队长的记录了吗?
Not even close.
差得远了
Excuse me.
打扰了
Agent coulson?
寇森特工?
Mr. Peterson,if you could put that bulldozer Back where you found it...
皮特森先生 请把那推土机 放回你找到它的地方...
We need you to suit up.
我们需要你穿上战服
This is a bad idea.
这主意可不怎么样
While I have you in a good mood,You should know
趁你心情还好 我得告诉你
that skye's trying to I.D. The agent That dropped her off at the orphanage.
丝恺想要找到把她送到孤儿院的特工
We agreed to protect her from the truth,So I told her you were looking into it.
我们一致认为不要让她知道真相 所以我告诉她你正在查这事
She may come to you.
她可能会来找你
One mistake at a time.
这个错误等我们忙完再跟你算
Agent coulson,agent may.
寇森特工 梅特工
Last time you saw her,you threw her into a brick wall.
你上次见她时把她扔进了一堵砖墙
Right.
对
First time around,I wasn't who I wanted to be,But now I get it.
第一次见面时 我不是自己想成为的那个人 不过现在我懂了
Having all this -- it's a privilege.
拥有这些 -- 是一种荣幸
And training to be an agent,working with S.H.I.E.L.D.,
受训成为一名特工 为神盾局工作
It's me trying to do better,trying to be  better.
我一直在努力做到更好
I just need you to give me a shot.
只需要你给我一个机会
Everyone deserves a second chance.
每个人都应该有第二次机会
But let me be clear -- there will not be a third.
但丑话说在前头--不会再有第三次
- Understood,sir. - Good.
- 明白 长官 - 很好
It's not good.
这可不好
At all.The guy was a ticking time bomb -- literally.
非常不好 这家伙整个一定时炸弹 一点不夸张
Hq wouldn't have sent him if he was still combustible.
要是他还像以前那么容易自爆 总部也不会派他过来
They must have found a way to stabilize him somehow.
他们肯定找到办法让他稳定下来
They stabilize his attitude?
能让他的态度都稳定下来?
'cause he was pretty hostile in union station.
当时他在联合车站可敌意十足呢
Well,it's not like We haven't opened up our doors to other people --
我们又不是第一次向那种人敞开大门
People with questionable track records.
那种有可疑历史的人
Not cool,but true.
不中听 却是事实
And don't worry about mike.
别担心迈克
He's a good guy.
他是个好人
Who's been in the centipede program.
他可是人体蜈蚣项目中的人啊
Exactly.He can give us some superpower backup.
没错 他能给我们超能力的支援
- Yeah. - Just saying,this could easily go sideways.
我只想说 这事太容易失控了
I mean,the last time we saw this guy,He was a raging homicidal maniac --
上次我们见这家伙 他还是个嗜血成狂的疯子...
He's standing right behind me,isn't he?
他就站在我身后 是不是?
Mr. Peterson,this is agent grant ward.
皮特森先生 这位是格兰特・沃德特工
He's the man who shot you at union station.
在联合车站 就是他击中你的
Fitz-simmons designed the weapon he used,And I think you remember --
他用的武器是菲茨-西门斯设计的 这位我想你应该记得...
Kidnap victim.
被你绑架的受害者
- you  joined S.H.I.E.L.D.? - Yeah.
- 你加入了神盾局? - 是的
Turns out,guys in suits -- not so bad.
原来 黑衣人们--也不错
Look,I know union station could have gone another way.
我知道联合车站的事 可能以另一种方式结束
Another team might not have let me out of there alive.
换成另一队人 可能就不会让我活着出去了
I owe you -- all off you.
我欠你们的--欠你们所有人
That's bygones and water under a distant bridge far away.
那都是过去啦 逝者如斯 就让它过去吧
how's your son?
你儿子怎么样了?
Still with my sister.
还在我姐那里住
He thinks I'm working construction,But he's good,happy.
他以为我在做建筑工 他很好 很快乐
So,what do we have?
我们有哪些线索?
Not much on po.
关于坡的并不多
I checked his previously known addresses And old military contacts -- came up empty.
我查了他以前的地址和部队的熟人 一无所获
We've been looking for where po might be on the outside.
我们一直在找坡在外面的落脚点
Let's look at his life on the inside -- at the prison.
应该再留意一下他在里面的生活 --监狱里面
See if that gets us any leads.
看看这样能不能找到线索
Anything on the centipede soldiers?
人体蜈蚣士兵方面有什么发现?
We found a facial recog match on one of them.
我们在面部识别系统找到其中一个人
Name's brian hayward.
名叫布莱恩・海沃德
Stationed in afghanistan for three years,Then fell of the radar when he got back.
在阿富汗驻扎了三年 回国后杳无音讯
Only living relative -- sister,laura,Sophomore at the university of ohio.
唯一在世的亲属是他的妹妹 劳拉 俄亥俄州立大学二年级学生
She's our best shot at finding hayward.
她是我们找到海沃德的最佳途径
You and I will go talk to her.
你跟我去 找她谈谈
Have may set a course for cleveland.
让梅设定航向 飞到克利夫兰
With all the high-tech gadgets and gizmos at our disposal,
用惯了那些高科技的小玩意
It's easy to forget about the simple tools of the past.
过去的简单工具就被我们抛弃了
What can I do for you?
有什么能帮你的?
I'm just curious about what you want me to do,Where you need me.
我只是好奇你会让我做些什么 哪里需要我
Here,on the plane.
这里 飞机上
But shouldn't I be out in the field?
但我不是应该上战场吗?
I mean,that's why you brought me here,right?
这才是你叫我来的目的 对吗?
You'll get your chance.
你会有机会一展所长的
Right now I need you to go down to the lab for some tests.
现在你得去实验室做一些测试
I'm stable.
我很稳定
They already tested me at sci-ops.
在科技部他们已经给我做过测试了
I know.
我知道
I also know that using your powers takes a toll.
我还知道使用你的力量要付出代价
I need to understand your limits,For your sake as well as my team's.
我需要了解你的限度 为了你和我团队的安全着想
The lab's downstairs.
实验室就在楼下
I have to put away four times what I used to Just to keep my energy up.
我得吃以前四倍的食物才能保持精力
Uh,and after you use your strength?
那你运用过了超能力之后呢?
Maybe 10 times the food?
吃比平时多10倍的东西?
And I usually crash afterwards.
但过后我一般都筋疲力尽了
It's really hard on my body.
对身体摧残得很结实
Hard body.Got it.
身体 结实 收到
You do know we have equipment that can take measurements.No need to do it manually.
你明知道我们有仪器来测量尺寸 不用人工测量
my mistake.
我错了
Well,no matter.I'll send the numbers to you straight away.
没关系 我立刻把数据传给你
I need measurements to build you a diagnostic suit So we can monitor your vitals in the field.
要你的尺寸来制作诊断性战服 好让我们在战地中监控你的生命体征
As for fabrics,how does a polymer blend With 10 layers of treated composite material sound?
至于面料 10层处理过的 复合材料聚合物 怎么样?
Sounds great?
不错?
Yeah,it does,doesn't it?
是呢 确实不错 对吧?
Sorry.
对不起
I'm sorry.I was -- I was just looking at it,and --
对不起 我刚刚在看这个
Oh,no,it's okay.I'm used to it.
没关系 我习惯了
They tried to take it off me at the sci-ops facility.
在科技部基地他们还想把它弄下来
Realized they couldn't do it without killing me.
后来发现只有杀了我才能把它弄下来
I'm afraid we're terribly curious.
我们都要好奇死了
How did they stabilize the extremis in you?
他们怎么稳定你的绝境病毒的?
- And keep you from exploding? - Yeah.
- 还让你不会爆炸? - 是的
Oh,that wasn't them.
那不是他们做的
That was you two.
是你们两个的功劳
- Come again? - What's that?
- 怎么回事? - 什么意思?
Your gun.
你们的枪
It somehow froze me Right at the moment I was about to explode,
在我将要爆炸时 把我冻结住
Helped my body absorb the serum,stabilize.
让我的身体吸收了血清 稳定下来
Your weapon saved my life.
你们的武器救了我的命
well...
呃...
All that,and it didn't even leave a scar,so...
而且 一点疤都没留下
- Well,I... - Well,I should think not.
- 我... - 我想也没有
Yeah,we couldn't have that,could we?
是呢 我们怎么能那样 是不是?
It would be a shame,Especially when you're so,well,formed and symmetrical.
那该多不好意思 特别是你... 身材如此匀称 面容又如此对称
And wh-when did you stop talking?
然后...你什么时候开始不说话的?
About three embarrassing sentences ago.
在你那三句丢人的话之前
Yes,right.
是呢 好吧
***
俄亥俄州立大学
"psychology of women: Unraveling the female psyche."
"女性心理学: 解读女性心理"
- That's an actual book? - It's a whole course.
- 真有这种书? - 是一整门课
Hayward's sister's in there now.
海沃德的妹妹正在上这门课
We'll be at the school in 10.
我们10点到学校
We'll catch her on her way out.
会在她下课时碰到她
Whole class... On women.
整门课...都讲女人
Time was,you just had to figure them out.
以前 你只能自己琢磨透她们
Solving the puzzle was half the fun.
解开迷题 本身就是一种乐趣
You solve a lot of puzzles in your day?
你解过很多谜题么?
A few. Some more worth it than others.
不少 有些比其他的更值得
One was... Especially rewarding.
有一个...尤其有许多回报
What happened?
后来怎么了?
I died.
我死了
I guess she wasn't level 7,sir?
我猜她不是七级特工吧 长官?
She was a cellist,second chair,portland symphony.
她是波特兰交响乐团的第二大提琴手
Saw her play whenever I was in town.
我只要去波特兰就去看她演出
Ever see a beautiful woman play the cello?
见过美丽的女人拉大提琴吗?
It's something else.
那简直不同凡响
She laughed at my jokes,too,which was a very nice bonus.
我讲的笑话她都会笑 这可是个超赞的额外收获
You know where she is now?
你知道她现在在哪?
Of course I do.
我当然知道
I'm sorry,sir.
为您遗憾 长官
I was gone for months.
我离开了几个月
The avengers thought I was dead,So I had to keep that up --
复仇者们都以为我死了 我必须保守这秘密
S.H.I.E.L.D. Protocol.
神盾局规章
It's probably better this way.
可能这样还比较好
Maybe if she'd been part of the agency...
要是她能成为神盾局的一员...
In my experience,that's just asking for trouble.
以我的经验来说 那等于自找麻烦
Coulson told me you were helping to,you know,Find my long-lost folks,so thanks.
寇森告诉我 你在帮我 找失散多年的父母 谢谢你
I'm glad you're in on this with me.It means a lot.
很高兴你在这件事上帮我 这对我很重要
Right,I can tell you're really into this.
好吧 我看得出来你真的"很"感兴趣
Um,I've done a lot of the heavy lifting already,Came up with a short list.
我把繁琐的部分都做完了 现在有了个短名单
- I thought you might -- We're on a mission,skye.
- 我想你可能... - 丝恺 我们在执行任务
Is this why you called me here?
你是因为这个把我叫来的吗?
No.
不是
I was just working on this while I waited for you.
等你的时候我才搞这个
Uh,I called 'cause I found something about po.
叫你过来是因为我发现坡的一些事情
Show me.
给我看看
Po only had one visitor during his prison stint -- her.
坡坐牢时只有一个人去探视 --就是她
You notice the outfit?
认得这身装扮吗?
Miles said a girl in a flower dress Asked him to hack S.H.I.E.L.D. This could be the same girl.
迈尔斯说有个穿花裙子的女孩让他 黑进神盾局系统 可能就是这个女孩
Can we hear the conversation?
能听到他们的对话吗?
That's the bummer -- There was no audio,but it's not a total loss.
很可惜--没有音频 但也不是毫无办法
I was able to use S.H.I.E.L.D.'s lip-reading program,Because we have one of those.
我利用了神盾局的唇语程序 因为我们真的有这么个程序
It didn't work on the girl Because she never looks up at the camera,
对那女孩不起作用 因为她一直没 抬头看镜头
But po did -- once -- and it caught this.
对坡管用--只有一次 于是就有了这个
The clairvoyant does not like  to be touched.
"预视者不喜欢被人打扰"
I wrote that down,So we don't have to hear that again --ever.
我记了下来 这样就不用重复听了
- The clairvoyant. - Yeah.Does that mean anything to you?
- 预视者 - 是的 这对你来说有意义吗?
But it means something to them --
但对他们来说肯定有意义
To po and whoever that woman is.
对坡和那个女人
Her name's raina.
她叫芮娜
You know her?
你认识她?
Yeah,she recruited me for centipede,
是啊 是她招募我去人体蜈蚣的
Came up to me at the hospital where I did my back therapy Out of the blue.
我在医院做背部理疗时找上我 非常突然
Told me she could change my life.
告诉我她能改变我的生活
Nice to cut my own meat again.
又能自己动手切肉了 真高兴
The steak was to your liking?
牛排还合胃口吗?
Overcooked,and the ambience...
过熟了 还有周围环境...
We're not here for the decor.
我们可不是为了这里的装修来的
We've stabilized the serum,added the implant,And now we need the clairvoyant's help In finding the key to stage three.
我们已经稳住了血清 添加了植入物 现在需要预视者帮忙找到第三阶段的关键
I've asked before.The clairvoyant has trouble seeing The man you're looking for and his weaknesses.
我之前已经问过了 预视者 看不清楚你要找的人和他的弱点
I don't mean to upset you.
我不是想让你心烦
It's the way of things.
但这确实是事实
This  is what's upsetting me.
这个才让我心烦
This S.H.I.E.L.D. Teams has destroyed two of our operations.
神盾局的队伍毁了我们的两个行动
We move every few days now to be safe.
我们现在每隔几天就要转移以确保安全
Which causes challenges for our maintenance problems.
这也给我们的维修问题带来挑战
We can't overstate the toll this takes on our soldiers.
我们士兵受到的极大影响 再怎么说也不为过
They are drained after every mission.
每次任务后他们都筋疲力竭
Our men need regular injections,constant upkeep.
我们的人需要定期注射 不断维护
Difficult when S.H.I.E.L.D. Has us on the run.
神盾局逼着我们一直逃亡的话 情况就很艰难了
Then it's time to stop running.
那是时候不再逃亡了
We're running her through our systems.
我们在系统里调查她
Maybe we can get an I.D.,but we're guessing She's centipede's recruiter and po's her latest recruit.
也许我们能得到身份信息 但我们猜测 她是人体蜈蚣的招募者 坡是她最近招的
Three super soldiers dive-bomb a prison,pluck him out?
三个超级士兵跳下来扔了个炸弹 炸开了监狱 把他救了出来?
He's her number-one draft pick.
他是她的首选目标
But why him?
但为什么是他?
Centipede's making more soldiers.
人体蜈蚣在造更多的士兵
Maybe they want po to coordinate them,lead them.
也许他们想要坡跟他们共事 领导他们
His background's tactical strategy.He fits the bill.
他有战略战术背景 符合要求
So,these guys have super soldiers,An expert military strategist,
所以 这些人有超级士兵 有一个军事战略专家
And a clairvoyant who can see the future.
还有一个预视者可以预见未来
Anyone else thinking about switching teams?
有人考虑换个团队吗?
They couldn't have a psychic.
他们不可能有预知能力
There are none on the index.They're a myth.
索引里没人有这个能力 只是个传说
So was thor.
雷神也是个传说啊
Maybe it's an alias.
也许这是个别名
Run it through our database and see if anything pops up.
在我们的数据库里查一下 看看有没有任何发现
Ward is approaching hayward's sister now.
沃德正在接触海沃德的妹妹
- Laura hayward? - That's me.
- 劳拉・海沃德? - 是我
Sorry to bother you,But I was hoping you could help me out.
很抱歉打扰你 但我希望你能帮我个忙
I hope so,too.
我很乐意
I'm looking for you brother,brian.
我在找你的哥哥 布莱恩
Have you seen him lately?
你最近见过他吗?
I'm -- I'm sorry.Who are you?
我...我很抱歉 你是谁?
Dan filch,ohio state gaming commission.
丹・费尔奇 俄亥俄州博彩委员会
We're trying to contact brian,tell him the good news.
我们正在尝试联系布莱恩 告诉他这一好消息
He won the lottery?
他彩票中奖了?
$50,000.
5万美金
Really?
真的吗?
And you're looking for him?
那你是在找他?
Don't you guys want to keep the money?
难道你们不想留着这些钱吗?
Sure,but we have to at least try and contact the winners Before the ticket expires.
当然想 但我们得在彩票过期前 至少尝试联系一下获奖者
Your brother's does in six days,so if you know where he is --
你哥哥还有六天时间 所以如果你知道他在哪儿...
I don't. Sorry. We're not close.
我不知道 抱歉 我们不太亲近
I haven't spoken to him since he got back from afghanistan.
自他从阿富汗回来 我都没有跟他说过话
Well,now you have a reason to -- 50,000 reasons,actually.
好吧 现在你有个理由了... 实际上 是5万个理由
So let us know if you hear from him.
如果你有了他的消息请联系我们
Okay.
好的
Not sure why you wanted to go with the lottery story,sir.
真不知道为什么你坚持要用彩票故事 长官
It's a tough sell.
很难让人买账的
Exactly.
正因如此
Nothing makes people more suspicious Than a handsome man offering them free money.
没有什么能比一个英俊男子免费送钱 更令人生疑的了
She's making the call now.
她已经开始打电话了
Brian,it's me.
布莱恩 是我
Some guy was just waiting for me at school,Said you won the lottery.
刚才有人在学校等我 说你中了彩票
I know,right?
我知道 对吧?
We're not that lucky.
我们哪有那么幸运
Is he local?
他在本地吗?
No. He's in oakland,california.
不在 他在加州奥克兰
Come in!
请进!
Oh,it almost looks homey.
这里很安逸啊
Is that ace?
那是艾斯吗?
What a cutie.
真可爱
He must be so proud of you,His dad working for S.H.I.E.L.D.
他一定很为你骄傲 他爸爸在为神盾局工作
Which he can't know with everything being classified.
但他没法知道 因为是绝密信息
That's all right.He knows I'm working.
没关系 他知道我在工作
Called him on his birthday And gave him all the "heroes of new york" action figures.
在他生日时我们通话了 我送了他全套"纽约之战英雄"手办
nice.
真好
Are you two close?
你们关系亲密吗?
We're a team.
我们是一个团队
I'd do anything for this little guy.
为了这个小家伙 我做什么都愿意
It's got to be the best feeling,
这一定是最美好的感觉
Son looking up to you Who wants to grow up to be just like you.
儿子崇拜你 希望长大后成为你这样的人
Yeah.
是啊
Looks like he's growing fast,though.
看起来他长得很快
You said you wanted your shot.
你说你想要个机会
Here it is.
机会来了
I won't let you down.
我不会让你失望的
- I think it's quite smart. - How does it feel?
- 我觉得看上去很醒目 - 感觉如何?
Feels good.
感觉很好
Comfortable.
很舒服
Having powers is cheating,but the suit's pretty cool.
拥有超能力是作弊 但这制服挺酷的
It's perfect for an array of tactical missions.
这适合多种战术任务
Yeah,also measures your heart rate,Systolic pressures,and glucose levels.
是啊 还能测量你心率 收缩压 还有血糖水平
All while providing State-of-the-art ballistic protection.
还有最先进的防弹功能
- Yeah. - Thanks.
- 是啊 - 谢了
- Oh,no. Thank you. - We've never been  so proud.
- 噢 不 谢谢你 - 我们从未如此骄傲过
Hayward's cellphone has been traced To an abandoned factory about eight miles from here.
海沃德的电话被追踪到 距离这里八英里的一个废弃工厂里
Probably centipede's new lab.
可能是人体蜈蚣的新实验室
Certainly been there m.O. -- We destroy one factory,
显然是他们的习惯手法 我们毁了一家工厂
They set up another,putting us back to square one.
他们再另建一个 我们又回到原点
This time,I want answers.
这一次 我要个答案
Means we go in quiet,Do minimal damage to the facility and the people inside.
所以我们要悄悄潜入 对里面的设备和人员做最小伤害
Ward,may,you'll go in through the west entrance.
沃德 梅 你们从西侧入口进去
Mr.Peterson and I will enter through the loading dock.
皮特森先生和我从装卸口进
You'll run the back end from outside.
你们在外面盯着后门
We're doing this just us?
就我们这些人来干?
We've been playing whack-a-mole with these guys Since ward first picked me out of my van.
自从沃德把我从我的货车里弄出来 我们就一直在和这些人玩打地鼠的游戏
Shouldn't big S.H.I.E.L.D. Be sending in backup?
难道神盾局不给我们派后援吗?
Trust me,they already did.
相信我 他们已经派了
Let's move.
行动吧
No pressure.
别有压力啊
***
加州 奥克兰
- We alone here? - It appears so.
- 这里只有我们吗? - 看来如此
The only heat signatures we're reading are yours.
我们发现的唯一热源就是你们的
But there's a weird electronic signal.I'm trying to isolate it.
但这里有个奇怪的电子信号 我在把它分离出来
Place looks emptied out.
这地方看起来被清空了
Think we're too late?
我们来晚了吗?
Fitz,dial hayward's number.
菲茨 打海沃德的电话
Find out.
确认一下
Uh,sir,you've got company.
长官 你们那里有敌情
Yeah,we do.
是啊 的确是
Coming your way.
正赶去你们那里
Usually packs a bigger punch.
一般杀伤力要大得多啊
Yeah,I remember.
是啊 我记得
What's happening?
发生了什么?
His systolic and diastolic pressures are dropping.
他的收缩压和舒张压在骤降
Heart rate's plummeting,as well.
心率也在下降
Sir,he's in bad shape.
长官 他的情况不佳
Between the physical exertion and this wound,His vitals are dangerously low.
由于体力消耗和外伤 他的主要器官现在都很危险
Who's behind centipede?
人体蜈蚣的幕后是谁?
Who's doing this?!
是谁干的?!
I won't say anything.I promise.
我什么也不会说的 我保证
No! Please!
不! 拜托!
Don't do th--
别...
That's mike peterson,one of our first subjects.
那是迈克・皮特森 我们的第一批实验者之一
He hasn't been injected with the serum in awhile,But he still has his powers.
他已经很久没有注射血清了 但他还有超能力
No.
不
What he has is your key to stage three.
他有的是你们通向第三阶段的关键
The one on the left is akela amador's.
左边的是艾克拉・阿玛多的
Hayward's is on the right.
右边的是海沃德的
Now,his prosthetic was slightly damaged,But based on digital reconstruction,
现在 他的假体轻微受损 但基于数字重建
We can now confirm That the technology is virtually identical.
我们现在可以确认用的是同一种技术
Hayward's prosthetic has the same internal power source,
海沃德的假体和阿玛多有相同的内部能源
Backscatter capabilities,and biomechanics as amador.
相同的背散射透视功能和生物动力
So centipede also designed the eye implant?
所以人体蜈蚣还设计了眼球移植物?
These guys are serious multitaskers.
这些人还真是多面手啊
Who's akela amador?
艾克拉・阿玛多是谁?
Former S.H.I.E.L.D. Agent,The first person we encountered with this eye technology,
神盾局前任特工 我们接触到的 第一位有这种眼球植入物的人
A good agent who was forced to do some bad things.
好特工被迫做了坏事
We helped her.
我们帮了她
Kind of a pattern with you guys.
挺像你们的处事风格
So then those soldiers at the warehouse Were forced to attack us through that eye thing?
所以那些仓库里的士兵是 被迫袭击我们的 被眼球控制?
They were getting orders.
他们接到了命令
When the tide turned in our favor,
当势头偏向了我们之后
Centipede flipped hayward's kill switch,Told the other guys to run.
人体蜈蚣启动了海沃德的杀人开关 告诉其他人逃跑
Can you track the eye feed like before,find their location?
你能像之前一样追踪假眼的信号 找到他们的位置吗?
Nope -- they've upgraded since amador.Their feed's untraceable now.
不能 他们自从阿玛多之后就升级了 他们的信号现在不可追踪
Their technology keeps advancing at a disturbingly rapid pace.
他们技术发展速度快得惊人
They must have endless manpower,resources.
他们一定有无尽的人力物力资源
And someone with a fat wallet.
而且还要很有钱
Po's the strategist.Raina's the recruiter.Perhaps this clairvoyant's the money.
坡是战略家 芮娜是招募者 也许这个预视者就是提供钱的那个
That makes sense.
有道理
If I could see the future,I'd go straight to las vegas.
如果我能看到未来 我就直奔赌城
Whoever's behind them may or may not be psychic,But they're one step ahead of us every time.
不管幕后是谁 是不是个预知未来的人 但他们每次领先我们一步
I need to update hq.
我需要汇报总部
This is bigger than we thought.
这事比我们想象得严重
I spoke with the clairvoyant.
我刚跟预视者通了话
And?
然后呢?
I'll share the information when the time is right.
我会在适当的实际共享信息的
I would love to hear much more than just information.
我想听到的可不仅仅是那些信息
Will you... Tell me what he's like?
你会...告诉我他什么样吗?
Never.
不可能
The last person who tried to learn these things Got a knife for it.
上一个想知道这些事的人 挨了一刀
I don't want to have to do that again,raina.
我不想再那么做了 芮娜
You have such pretty eyes.
你有双很美丽的眼睛
I understand.
我了解
You can't even whisper to me about him.
你连悄悄和我谈起他都不行
No,I can't.
的确不行
But I did tell the clairvoyant about you.
但我和预视者提起过你
Spoke at length about your many virtues.
提及你的许多优点
How sweet.
真是贴心
- I'll pour you a scotch. - Don't ever do that again.
- 给你倒杯苏格兰威士忌吧 - 永远都别再那样做!
Brandy,then?
那就白兰地?
When we're out in the field,Your head needs to be on the op,not on me.
在外执行任务时 你脑子里要想着 任务本身 而不是我
Time-out.Still playing catch-up here.
暂停一下 我没跟上你的节奏
What are you talking about?
你在说什么?
You taking a punch for me?
你替我挨了一拳
I don't need your protection.
我不需要你的保护
You think I don't know that?
你以为我不知道?
I took that punch 'cause you're faster than me.
我之所以挨了一拳 是因为你比我快
You could do more good on your feet.
你的移动能起的作用更大
It was tactical,not personal.
这是战术需要 与私人感情无关
My mistake.
是我想多了
I am not some recruit who can't separate church from state.
我可不是公私不分的菜鸟
I'm on the same page as you.
我和你想法一样
So don't flatter yourself.
所以别自命不凡了
Sorry.I didn't mean to crash.
抱歉 我不是故意不请自来
What do you want?
怎么了?
- This about that thumb drive again? - No.
- 又是那个U盘的事? - 不是
Good.
很好
Look,I get that you don't want to help with that Loud and clear,big neon,flashing lights.
我知道帮我这个忙你心不甘情不愿 你已经做得再明显不过了
But I didn't ask,okay?
但又不是我要找你的
- Coulson -- Coulson doesn't want to tell you the truth.
- 寇森... - 寇森对你隐瞒真相
The truth is...
真相就是...
You have to decide why you're here.
你要想清楚你为什么加入神盾局
We have a mission,and it's not to find your parents.
我们有任务在身 这个任务并不是 寻找你的生身父母
If you can't put aside your personal attachments,Then you shouldn't be here.
如果你不能把私人问题抛开 那就不该待在飞机上
Oh,come on in.
请进
You doing okay?
你没事吧?
Afraid I won't be...
恐怕我没法帮忙了
Much good to you for the next couple days.
至少在接下来的两三天不行
That's understandable.
可以理解
You went above and beyond at that warehouse,Had our backs more than once.
在仓库里你已经竭尽所能 不止一次救了我们
Thank you,sir. But I know centipede's still out there.
谢谢夸奖 长官 但我知道 人体蜈蚣依然横行在外
No,we still got a lot of work to do.
我们任重道远
True. But according to your s.O.,hard work's your specialty.
没错 但据你的督导官说 努力工作是你的强项
Said you train 24/7.
据说你日以继夜地训练
I want to be the best.
我想做到最好
And that's admirable.
令人敬佩
But you hadn't left the training facility Since you got there,
但你到训练基地后就没离开过
Which means you haven't seen your son since union station.
也就是说联合车站事件之后 你就没见过你儿子了
Ace is fine.
艾斯过得挺好
We...We talk all the time.
我们...我们经常聊天
But you haven't been to see him. Why?
但你还没见过他 这是为什么?
Mike!
迈克!
Because the last time he saw me...
因为上次他看见我的时候...
I was a monster.
我是个怪物
My kid saw that.
我儿子全都看到了
You can't fix that from here.
你在这里也没法弥补啊
And staying away,not being there...
不见你儿子 不陪着他...
I've seen firsthand The kind of damage that can do.
我亲眼见过这样做 会对另一方所造成的伤害
The last thing I want to do is hurt ace.
我绝不想伤害艾斯
He's...He's my son,but... Maybe he's better off without me.
他是...他是我儿子 但是... 也许没有我他会过得更好
I don't think that's true.
不是这样的
When I took this job,I made a choice,The same choice everyone else here made --
刚进入神盾局时 我做了个决定 和这里的所有人一样 --
This life over the other one,The one with holiday dinners and pta meetings,recitals.
我选择了这种生活 而不是另一种 那种有节日晚餐 家长会和演奏会的生活
It's not easy.
这种生活不容易
But if the time comes to make the hard call,It's simpler.
但在危急关头要做艰难决定时 这样会容易些
But you have a son.
可你有一个儿子
You have someone waiting for you to come home.
有人期盼着你回家
You need to think about that.
你要想想这些
You need to think about him.
你要为他想想
Before you make your choice.
然后再做你的决定
Hello?
喂?
Hey,ace.
嗨 艾斯
Dad!
爸爸!
It is so good to hear your voice,buddy.
听到你的声音真好 伙计
And I got some good news -- I'm gonna get to come home and see you for a bit.
有个好消息 我可以回家看看你
Awesome!
太棒了!
Then maybe you can meet my new friend.
那你就能见到我的新朋友了
She said she knows you.
她说她认识你
She's here right now.
她就在旁边
Ace,who's there with you?
艾斯 谁和你在一起
Where's your aunt mindy?
明迪姑姑呢?
Hello,mike.
你好 迈克
Remember when I told you I could change your life?
记得吗 我说过我可以改变你的生活
They want a trade -- ace for his father.
他们想要交易 用艾斯交换他的父亲
They've set a time and a place.
讲好了时间地点
Bloody savages.
这群该死的禽兽
They want to experiment on him,Determine how he still has his abilities.
他们想在他身上做试验 找出他维持超能力的方法
And we're gonna let them?
我们就听之任之?
- We've fought these guys before. - We don't have a choice.
- 我们之前和这些家伙有过交手 - 我们别无选择
The instructions they gave mr.Peterson were very specific.
他们给皮特森先生下的指令很具体
I called hq,told them to stand down.
我给总部打了电话 让他们别插手
- Stand down? - So we take them alone.
- 不插手? - 所以全靠我们自己
We should at least have a hostage-rescue unit In support of this.
我们至少需要一个人质解救小组的支援
They said they would murder my son.
他们说他们会杀了我儿子
If we make one wrong move.
如果我们有一点不照做的话
Any electronics,any comms,any sign of surveillance And they'll terminate the arrangement.
如果发现任何电子设备 通信仪器 或者监视工具 他们就会撕票
I'll give myself up,no problem,get him back.
我可以用自己作交换 只要可以救我儿子就没关系
I can figure it out from there.
我之后再想办法
You're still recovering.
你还在恢复阶段
We can't just hand you over to them like that,can we?
我们不能就这样把你交给他们 不是吗?
Fitz-simmons have a non-electronic method Of tracking him.
菲茨和西蒙斯有个不用 电子设备的办法跟踪你
Simmons has fabricated an odorless scent.
西蒙斯精心制作了一种无味气体
I have an instrument which can detect it.
我发明了一个可以检测到它的仪器
Works like a bloodhound,Can track someone from over 50 kilometers.
就像警犬一样 能在超过50公里的范围跟踪目标
After we make the trade,We'll be able to follow mr. Peterson.
完成交易后 我们可以跟着皮特森
Buy him some time to get his strength back.
好让他有时间恢复体力
We'll find him.
我们会找到他
I don't care what happens to me.
我不在乎自己会怎样
As long as my boy is...
只要我儿子...
I promise you,we're gonna get your son back.
我向你保证 我们会救出你儿子
At least let me escort him out for the exchange.
至少让我护送他去做交易
Mr. Peterson requested me.
皮特森先生要求我陪着他
I'm comfortable with that,and if things go south,I need you back here,taking point on the team.
我不介意 如果情况不妙 我需要你在这里指挥全组
Is ward in position?
沃德就位了吗?
Yes.
是的
But I don't like any of this.
但我不喜欢这样
There'd be something wrong with you if you did.
如果你喜欢 那才有问题
Once the swap happens,I'll fire up my equipment.
交易一结束 我就会开启设备
We'll be able to track you wherever they take you.
不管他们把你带到哪儿 我们都会找到你
Just don't do anything that'll endanger my son.
只要别做威胁我儿子安全的事就好
We won't,but we want to make sure Ace has his dad at the end of the day,too.
不会的 但我们也想让艾斯 事情结束之后还能再见到他父亲
Time to go.
是时候了
My team won't let you down.
我的团队不会让你失望
It wasn't supposed to go down like this.
事情本不该发展成这样
I'm gonna make this right,I swear.
我会弥补的 我发誓
Damn it.
该死
Hello,mike.It's been awhile.
你好 迈克 好久不见
Your son is adorable,and he looks just like you.
你儿子真可爱 和你真是一个模子里刻出来的
I don't believe I've had the pleasure.
我似乎还没这个荣幸认识你?
Lucky for you.
算你运气好
I have to thank you,mike,For holding up your end of the deal.
我得谢谢你 迈克 谢谢你信守承诺
Let's just make the trade.
让我们交易吧
Give us ace,and you can have him.
把艾斯给我们 你可以带他走
Oh,that wasn't the deal.
这可不是我们的交易
I'm so sorry.
我很抱歉
Let me know when I can activate comms and the tracker.
可以启动通信设备和跟踪器时告诉我
What's happening here,mike?
怎么回事 迈克?
Well,in exchange for his son,we asked mike to deliver you.
为了交换他的儿子 我们让迈克把你交出来
I'm not at full strength,But I can still crush your throat.
就算没用十成的力 我也可以捏断你的喉咙
New deal!My son for your  life.
新交易! 用我儿子换你的命
Sadly,my employer cares no more for my life than your son's.
可惜 我的雇主根本不在乎我的死活
If I die,so does he,And his death will be so much worse.
如果我死了 那艾斯也会死 但他的死亡将会痛苦得多
You need to let her go.
放开她吧
I told them they could have me.
我告诉过他们可以抓走我
But they want you.
但他们想要你
Why do they want you?
他们为什么想要抓你?
I don't know,but if you kill this woman,You'll never see your son again.
我不知道 但如果你杀了这女人 你就再也见不到你儿子了
But how will I look him in the eye?
我要如何面对他?
How will I explain what I did?
向他解释我都做了些什么?
We talked about this.
我们谈过这个问题
I'm so sorry.
真抱歉
Let's finish this.
让我们结束这一切
Dad!
爸爸!
There's his son.
他儿子在那儿
Oh,thank god.I have no stomach for this.
天哪 我的心脏可真受不了了
On my mark,activate comms and tracker.
等我命令 开启通讯设备和追踪器
If there had been any other way...
如果有任何其它选择...
You made the only choice you had.
你别无选择
What happened?They've taken coulson.
发生了什么? 他们带走了寇森
All right,call it in.We need backup.
汇报总部 我们需要支援
I have a shot.
我瞄准了
Do not engage.They'll kill coulson.
别开枪 他们会杀了寇森的
Stand down. I'll contact hq.
别轻举妄动 我会联系总部
You okay?
你没事吧?
I'm fine,dad.
我很好 爸爸
S.H.I.E.L.D. Hq,this is S.H.I.E.L.D. Rg422.
神盾局RG422呼叫总部
We need immediate satellite support.
我们即刻需要卫星支援
Ace,I've got to make something right.
艾斯 我要去纠正一些错误
Daddy loves you so much,okay?
爸爸非常爱你
Stay with skye.You remember skye,right?
和丝恺在一起 你记得丝恺 对吗?
Keep him safe.
保护他的安全
Take care of my boy!
照顾我儿子
No!!
不!!
mike!
迈克!
Where's coulson?
寇森在哪儿?
Oh,my god.
天哪
Coulson.
寇森
-=http://bbs.sfile2012.com=- Proudly Presents
-=伊甸园美剧 http://bbs.sfile2012.com=- -=伊甸园字幕站 http://ytet.org=- 荣誉出品 本字幕仅供学习交流，严禁用于商业途径
We land in half an hour.
我们半小时后降落
Good. The sooner we begin,the better.
很好 越早开始越好
Whatever this is,whatever you think you're doing,It won't work.
无论你的意图是什么 你都不会得逞
I won't give you what you want.
我不会给你你们想要的
You will.
你会
And we want is simple.
我们想要的很简单
We want you to tell us about the day after you died.
我们想知道在你死后的那天发生了什么
-=http://bbs.sfile2012.com/bbs=- Sync: YTET- 好大一个坑
-=YTET-伊甸园字幕组=- 翻译:安 梨涡浅笑 煮小蛋蛋 怡豆 校对:Don't panic! 三周后1月8日回归! 时间轴: 好大一个坑